Okay, Erin, this is with narration. Thank you for enjoying this.
So this is the edge of our house. It's like a weird
bunglery type thing. So there's this long drive. You come down,
it's semi detached. That's next door. This is all us. So it's
very odd. So it's dining point. Really ugly entrance, bizarre colour.
Hate the roof. But let's keep going. So when
you walk along here, that's our garage. Then there's a separate entrance here
for a standalone, like, let's call it
Granny flat. And then along here.
And again, we hate all this. It's really ugly. Maybe we extend
here. Who knows? Along here is the main
entrance. This is my daughter, as smiling as ever.
And then. So this is the hall. Ignore the greenhouse
sky. Don't worry about that. This is the main entrance.
So on the left hand side, we have. There's currently
a weird utility room. Because the kitchen is so small, there's no room.
We think we're going to make this a study.
So, very odd. And next to it,
very small bathroom, as in toilet.
Okay. And then we go, right, so this is the main entrance.
So big fireplace
here. There's also a fireplace here. There's two.
This is currently a lounge. Very strange size, doesn't quite function.
Ignore the mess. It's very messy. So lounge,
kind of an awkward size. That's just a tiny cupboard.
That's the side entrance. That is outside.
And then this wall, which we've often thought about knocking down,
go through to a very small kitchen.
This is curly. This is a very small kitchen.
And then this is the outside. This is where we bought the house. It's got
a really good garden, especially for central Brighton.
And so the idea is that we think what we'd like to do,
perhaps, is some kind of massive extension. So I
say massive. An extension. So, as you see, really ugly,
ugly, ugly, ugly. And then the idea is that there is
potential to go out, maybe to here, all the way along there, and make
one kind of grand room of some shape or form. So this is the side
entrance.
It goes out to back where we started. And then
this is where the house gets even stranger. So a small kitchen.
Not going to worry about upstairs because I don't think we're going to change anything
upstairs but this bit.
So there's this
door and then we basically have a
standalone bathroom, which we think would make sense as a utility room
because we're not quite sure whether there's another bathroom down here. This is under the
stairs. There's nothing there. Now on the left,
this is the standalone granny flat that we saw from the other side.
So this is a sensibly sized standalone thing with
a toilet. And that's the outside bit that you saw before.
And then this corridor, again, all dead space with
a number of spaces that make no sense. So there's a
storagey thing there and then this
second storage thing there, and then you have this room,
again, not making an awful lot of sense. So I think
the challenge is none
of it is very efficient. I think it's probably the easiest way to describe it.
And,
yeah, which walls we knock through. So whether it's this wall going to the kitchen,
clearly the kitchen needs to be longer. And this is a south facing garden,
but you wouldn't know with the light, because it's not
really being used to its best effect. So I think what we'd like
is some kind of extension thing there and
then some kind of refiguring of all of this. And the challenge is
just doing it in a cost effective way that makes any sense.
And as I said, the two architects we've had come look have said,
yeah, don't do the extension. This is big enough footprint. Just rejig
it. And a, I'm not convinced, and b, they didn't seem
to have an elegant answer on the what that would actually mean.
So, as I said, my preference would be that we do something
that takes us out here in some way, makes this less ugly and
makes it interesting. But the core guest requirement is we want a
grand room of some shape or form.
So I'll send it to you now. Thank you for enduring hope. That makes some
sense.