If you want to quickly add subtitles to your videos and take them from this
based on this research, now AI can learn to use digital
tools like to this and few or zero shot
settings when it comes to natural language processing tasks. You can do
it with AssemblyAI and it's going to be just a couple of lines of code
very quick. Based on your transcription that you submitted to AssemblyAI,
you're going to get time subtitles that you can upload to
YouTube or use on your local computer however you like.
The first thing that you want to do is to make sure that you have
the AssemblyAI SDK installed. And for that all you have
to do is go to your terminal and write down pip install
AssemblyAI and that will install the python SDK
of AssemblyAI. And then you want to make sure that you have a AssemblyAI
API key and that is free to get. So just head on to
AssemblyAI.com comma create an account and
you will get a free API key from AssemblyAI. And then
in your python file just import AssemblyAI
as AAI and then set your AssemblyAI
key, the API key here.
And then you just want to start a transcription job.
So create a transcriber object.
And on that I can start the transcription job. You can
either pass a video or audio file directly to AssemblyAI.
So the video I'm working with in this example
is this one. Can AI learn to use tools?
Well, maybe not physical one, but this is a 4k video and
it is 1.18gb, so it's
going to take some time to be uploaded to AssemblyAI instead.
You can just, if you're on Mac, you can start the quicktime player
and then say file export as audio
only and it will strip the audio of your video.
And then my audio is only 8.7
megabytes, so it's going to go much faster. So that's why I'm
going to pass the toolformer M four
a file to be transcribed.
And once the transcription is ready,
all I have to do is to say export subtitles srt.
So this will export the subtitles in the SRT format.
If you want it can also export them in the VTT
format. So I'll use the SRT format right now.
You don't have to pass anything to it, but if you want to specify
how many characters maximum you want on each caption,
you can specify chars per caption
variable. And this is going to be an integer so we
can specify it to be 100 to 50. I think
overall is generally between 81 hundred. So 50 would
be a bit short and 150 would be a bit long.
But we don't have to specify this, we'll just use a default value.
And then I'm just going to open a file.
I'll just call this subtitles srt with
write permission and
then write my subtitles in there and
then close the file. All right,
let's run this and see how it goes. All right, now that this is
done, let's go and take a look.
I can open it with text editor and this
is what it looks like. And this would be as you can see,
this is timed and it will be
accepted by anywhere that accepts the SRT files.
You can upload it to YouTube for example, with your video or as far
as I know, on the VLC player too. You can add subtitles
on top of a video that you have and that's how you
can get subtitles for your videos. In just how
many lines of code? 12345 lines of code.
I mean, just count this as one, you know, just writing it into
file. So that's it. If you have any questions,
make sure to leave them down below in the comments section.
If you want to learn more about this functionality, you can go to
the AssemblyAI documentation or the SDK documentation
on GitHub. I will make sure to leave links for you in the description below.
Thanks for watching and I will see you in the next video.