If you want to quickly add subtitles to your videos and take them from this
based on this research, now AI can learn to use digital tools
like to this in few or zero shot settings.
When it comes to natural language processing tasks, you can do it
with AssemblyAI and it's going to be just a couple of lines of code very
quick. Based on your transcription that you submitted to AssemblyAI,
you're going to get time subtitles that you can upload to
YouTube or use on your local computer however you like.
The first thing that you want to do is to make sure that you have
the AssemblyAI SDK installed. And for that all
you have to do is go to your terminal and write down pip
install AssemblyAI and that will install the python SDK
of AssemblyAI. And then you want to make sure that you have a AssemblyAI
API key and that is free to get. So just head on to AssemblyAI.com
comma create an account and you will get a free API key from
AssemblyAI. And then in your python file
just import AssemblyAI
as AAI and then set your AssemblyAI
key, the API key here.
And then you just want to start a transcription
job. So create a transcriber
object. And on that I can start the transcription job.
You can either pass a video or audio file directly to
AssemblyAI. So the video I'm working with in
this example is this one.
Can AI learn to use tools? Well, maybe not physical one,
but this is a 4k video and it is 1.18gb,
so it's going to take some time to be uploaded to AssemblyAI
instead. You can just, if you're on Mac, you can
start the quicktime player and then say file export
as audio only and it will strip the audio of your
video. And then my audio is only 8.7
megabytes, so it's going to go much faster. So that's why I'm going
to pass the tool former m four a
file to be transcribed. And once the transcription
is ready, all I have to do is to say export
subtitles srt. So this will export the subtitles
in the SRT format if you want. It can also export
them in the VTT format. So I'll use the SRT format
right now. You don't have to pass anything to it, but if you
want to specify how many characters maximum you want
on each caption, you can specify chars
per caption variable. And this is going to be an integer
so we can specify it to be 100 to 50.
I think overall is generally between 81 hundred.
So 50 would be a bit short and 150 would be
a bit long. But we don't have to specify this, we'll just use
a default value. And then I'm just going to open
a file. I'll just call this subtitles srta
with write permission and
then write my subtitles in there and
then close the file. All right,
let's run this and see how it goes. All right, now that this is
done, let's go and take a look.
I can open it with text editor and
this is what it looks like. And this would be as you
can see, this is timed and it will be
accepted by anywhere that accepts the SRT files.
You can upload it to YouTube for example with your video or
as far as I know, on the VLC player too. You can add subtitles on
top of a video that you have and that's how
you can get subtitles for your videos. In just
how many lines of code? 12345 lines of code.
I mean, just count this as one, you know, just writing it into
file. So that's it. If you have any questions,
make sure to leave them down below in the comment section.
If you want to learn more about this functionality, you can go
to the AssemblyAI documentation or the SDK documentation
on GitHub. I will make sure to leave links for you in the description below.
Thanks for watching and I will see you in the next video.